

DEEP LEARNING ENGINEER

□(+1) 650-255-2445 | Modgka@gmail.com | Alechodgkinson.com | Dodgka | Dodg

## Summary\_

A deep learning engineer with experience rapid prototyping, implementing state of the art models, and writing technical reports. I like to work on cool projects which means I touch every part of the technology stack nearly every day.

# Education

#### **Rensselaer Polytechnic University**

Aug 2013 - Dec 2016

B.S. IN APPLIED MATHEMATICS, MINOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

# **Experience**

Panasonic Beta Mar 2018 - Present

ACTION GENOME HOME, PROJECT LEAD

- Managing activities in a team of seven, including engineering, process development, and data recording, and proposal writing.
- Developed hardware prototype using Raspberry Pi and a variety of sensors. Wrote custom firmware to communicate between the Pi and sensors over I2C Bus.
- Wrote software to cleanly record and package video and sensor data into a video container for easy distribution.
- Developed a Flask-based front-end for recording synchronized data across multiple sensor suites, speeding up recording time by 50x.
- Wrote proposal for a workshop at the ECCV2020 conference.

#### DOORGYM: A SCALABLE DOOR OPENING ENVIRONMENT AND BASELINE AGENT, PROJECT LEAD

- Developed initial proof of concept for door opening simulation.
- Developed a novel CNN-based vision pipeline for regressing 3D door knob location from multiple views. Achieved an accuracy of ±1.7 cm in simulation, accurate enough for an agent to open a door.
- Transferred vision neural network trained in simulation to real doorknobs with an accuracy of ±4.95cm.
- Performed ablation tests to verify the necessity of each component in the vision network pipeline.
- Created infrastructure for interfacing neural networks with the Baxter Robot platform.

## **Panasonic Silicon Valley Labs**

Mar 2017 - Mar 2018

#### DEEP LEARNING ENGINEER

- Developed a novel post-processing filter for image codecs resulting in a 20%+ reduction in bitrate.
- Implemented end-to-end deep learning models for image compression using Tensorflow.
- Evaluated and adapted state of the art deep learning models for alleviating catastrophic forgetting in neural networks.
- Developed face tracking/identification software for a robotic platform running in real time at 30 FPS.
- Authored technical papers and descriptions for three individual patents.
- Developed proof of concept demonstration using deep learning based monocular image height estimation running on a Raspberry Pi for presentation to CEO.
- Developed a gesture detection model and API for use in a smart home setting.

**Junior.io** Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

## DEEP LEARNING INTERN

- Architected the backend of a content based music recommender system for an open space environment using a PostgreSQL database, the Spotify API, and git for source control.
- Built a neural network to classify user preferences based on previous listening habits in Keras.

# **Projects**

### **Pixel Recursive Super Resolution Implementation**

PERSONAL Mar 2017 - Apr 2017

Implemented "Pixel Recursive Super Resolution" using Tensorflow, to "enhance" low resolution images by adding missing details to generate
higher resolution images.

Reproduced results of the original authors using multiple different metrics such as PSNR and SSIM.

**Programming** Python, JavaScript, C++, LaTeX

**Machine Learning** PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, NumPy, OpenCV

Web Flask, HTML5, CSS3, React, P5.js

Other Technologies Git, Docker, AWS, ZeroMQ

APRIL 28, 2020 1